hello you do and welcome to your first
microsoft visual basic tutorial
editorial I'm gonna be introducing
myself letting us know what a
programming language is probably
beginners out there who are just looking
to learn a language
let you know that about about the dotnet
framework and
about what we're gonna be doing in these
tutorials now that's good you started
my name is Sam and I run the YouTube
channel YouTube dot com slash
on my came in I'm currently have about
80 videos
and they're over Visual Basic Java
visual c plus plus and C sharp so you
can go ahead and go check that out if
you want
how they make a lot more césar videos
in the future so you want to go and
subscribe
and another man advertised his over what
is
a programming language what a
programming language does
is aid uses code that the
developer rights and it makes the
decision what I mean by this
is that it can solve a problem make a
decision
for the user and to do this it uses
data and algorithms all programming
language use data and algorithms
it takes that data push it through an
algorithm
and did you get it output so now that
you know a little bit about
what any programming languages but I
signed you what the dotnet framework is
now the dotnet framework was a made by
Microsoft
and a what they wanted to do
what they wanted to create a programming
language or not language don't agree
a framework that was independent the
Windows
and what I mean by this is that when you
create a program that runs on the dotnet
framework
it is not dependent on the system it
runs
on the framework itself which is kind of
like a virtual machine if you've ever
used
used a virtual machine or a free Java
programmers
it's like the Java Virtual Machine he
keeps independent have the computer that
is running on
but in my opinion is a lot more
effective in the Java Virtual Machine
in as a lot better job now I'm may vary
to this but
Visual Basic is a very high level
language what I mean by this is that
is easy to understand is very much like
English
and is when the highest program highest
level languages that
I know and an example the low-level
language would be
c plus plus or something similar that
now I am
what we gonna be doing this tutorial
well
will not listen to all the tutorials
will start off by covering
data types variables were gonna do some
math
we're gonna work on I'm simple steps to
begin with Justin the Consul
in there were gonna move on to Windows
Forms now this is one of the things I
love about Visual Basic
is that its easy to make windows in and
Mike
and c plus plus or Python or
other problem there's a job there you
don't have to use the code to make your
Windows in
the Visual Basic I D E you can just drag
and drop objects on the winners
and the I D E will automatically
generate code for you
that creates that window so that when
you run the program
it looks exactly like you want and now
if you do it by yourself such as the
language like Java
sometimes it's hard to see to visualize
what you wind is going to look like
by just by typing the conies important
so this is one the reasons I like Visual
Basic
and all the visual are going which is in
Visual Studio
so I'm you guys have any questions
in guiding them in the comments I I'll
be monitoring
these videos on the New Boston and I'm
I'll try to answer as many questions as
I can I know they're going to be a lot
as he has a lot to subscribers and have
your stay tuned
for the next tutorial also
one more thing is that you guys will
learn more about
the languages in that run on the dotnet
framework or just other stuff
about development with this you can go
ahead and head over to the
Microsoft developers website at
investing in da Microsoft com
to read up about their languages they
have and I'm
the new stuff and the new releases that
they come out with so I'll
that's about it thanks for watching and
don't forget to comment like and
subscribe