hello youtube and welcome to your second
visual basic tutorial
in this tutorial I'm recovering how to
install the
Visual Basic 2010 Express I D E does
have nobody to go
and we'll just searched visual Basic
exit the first thing that comes up is
max after Comp Sci us
expressed slash downloads when you go
ahead click that
here's the Dallas Page when it come over
here to
Visual Basic 2010 Express click on that
and select the language that you can be
using I'm you using English
so good 6a and now open it up
you know ask you to allowed to make
changes squeaky s you extract the files
you know
take a little bit to set up the
insulation components and when you start
this you may need to install a dotnet
framework 4.0
and I if that's the case I'll take a
little bit longer then I'll take me
so this is with us to finish to take a
second here
okay here's our setup window get this
out of the way
care when you can choose whatever you
want to do with this yes any information
about my sex
setup experience Microsoft obviously
that sectors yes
then click Next yet nobody ever reaches
the way
click Next and it says that's
are ready to start is Visual Basic now
you made since I'll be done it for me
because I said
and to downsize fifty four megabytes
says go and it's all this now
I'm gonna go ahead and pas the video
here and I'll come back once it's done
and you can see the download is almost
finished
now it will start installing
the Visual Basic I D E souls go ahead
let that run
and deposit here
and come back which is finished with
that as finished
you should see a Windows like this
that's go ahead and click Exit
and now
we wait for this can adhere to your
start menu
and they can see it burden catch
you can open up Visual Basic 2010
Express and mine says this part is I
since years will not say that
if you just your justice on this for the
first time but you need to do
is an ego up to help and research
products
this is a preprocess I'm used to give
them your email in like your name
and what you're interested in developing
and I'll give you just a free license
key and you can use that to register
your product
so I thanks for watchin and don't forget
to comment like and subscribe