hella YouTube and welcome to your third
microsoft visual basic tutorial
and this juror we'll be taking a look at
the iDEN see what has
that we can use to make programs so it's
not me started
appears we have our File menu
which you see a lot now the program's we
have under the File
section we have new project we can
create a new project
obviously you can open a project you can
open a file such as a class
or in a solution you can close out it
was you
currently working on you can close your
project save stated I didn't save our
you can export template know what this
means is that but say you create
a Windows Forms or with a spoon and you
will be able to use that same design
threw out a bunch different product
products you can
explore the template and so when you go
in there to create a new project you can
select that template and everything
already be made for you
you could argue recent files the recent
files
recent projects and solutions and you
can
exit the program I can use a shortcut
are forced to do that
nope you know Edit menu we have I do
redo was pretty self-explanatory cut
copy paste it into your selection
you can select our you can quick find
making quick
replace know what this is what this does
is
it pops at this window and you can
search for a certain
string this is very usefull if you
forget where something is
you gotta find it you can also use quick
replace
to you replace something by searching
for streaming in replacing it with
another string
appear in our view we can be the start
page which is this right here
it gives you the get started and it's
just some stuff that you can
see other makes us website or teach you
how to use this you know the latest news
you can enable ours RSS feed if you want
to get news from microsoft
I can do other Windows you can view the
database explore
the aerialists which the area this is
right down here you the Properties
window
which will show up right here once we
start making programs Solution Explorer
which is all we have open right here
already
and you can view the toolbox which is
what you use
to add controls your forms you can view
the web browser and you can also find
results
so im
you can change the options deberg if you
want you can go and look to these a
message that if you want
and got your tools
you can view extensions for Visual Basic
we will be using
any extensions you can go to Settings
you can you basic settings
expert settings reset or import and
export settings
if you want to if you'd like to do that
so you get a setting style
he will use that in good import that
customize it options as computing
options and I just wanna make sure you
guys have something set
so go ahead and expand text editor and
we were all languages
and general I think it is
Beach so
come down here to basic and you can see
a box right here called my numbers make
sure that is checked
now what we wanted why we want to check
this is so that later on we're making
our programs
if we weren't airs the airless is gonna
tell us what line number that's on
is be very useful to be able to see the
line numbers right next year code
so ago and click OK on that and you're
so have
under window you can for window so what
that does
is let's just say which I start a job
here you start putting
and you can see there we've got several
boxes to choose from
to a create a different sides and
possible I D E swords can choose the
central
parts which is where it was before I we
can also
doctor we do which is what we did hide a
weirdo
are our clothes are documents soviet
more more than one class open
a or something else you can close all
those out it shows you the
windows that open right now any
compulsory set you lay out if you want
now the Help menu
he you have the option to have you help
manage help settings
go to forums or look at samples and
other stuff like that you can mess out
that if you want now down here in this
bar
we have are new project
open file save our and some other things
like
Solution Explorer properties with the
toolbox just that that was re-appear
in this menu just down here so that blue
need to access a quick it's gonna be
there
is so the most commonly use controls now
we also have
the a realist which also are there is no
programs also the warnings
what a warning is is it really it really
isn't air
but it's something that could cause air
when you run your program
and over here we have our solution
explorer which I
basically we're solution is is it to
file they can hold a budget projects
or one project if you'd like inside the
Stratus you have classes
and I'm forms and other stuff
so I'm if you want to you can go ahead
and mess around seven this stuff in dide
to go ahead and get familiar with that
for move on to the next it took tutorial
and don't forget to comment like and
subscribe
thanks for watching