hello youtube and welcome to your fourth
microsoft visual basic tutorial in this
tutorial we can actually start
programming
now to start of we're gonna go ahead and
click new project
and this will open up our new project
window now here you have to try to get
this in the frame
we're gonna go ahead and use it started
place and Visual Basic in a select a
console application
now to do with this one's applications
that has a little a lot occurred at
are already pre made for you and this
could confuse you even more
if you're a beginner program and you've
never going to language so I'm
I was going to go ahead and name this
wide VB
hello world and now
go ahead and click okay and start
loading
our project here's a module that we
created
they could see inside our module it
starts with module module one
that's the name of the file and it
started and
into the in module that everything going
to make
is gonna have to start with the type
that is
like a class is a class MyClass as
always it had to end with
in Dubai class and for instance years
are
main so here said main
and ends with inset now and I said
class MyClass in my class AB class
MyClass
the and class so I screwed up a bit but
a
going to start in every program
there has to be what's called a made sub
now what this does is it's the first
step that runs no matter what
the program has to have a starting point
you can still create about two sides and
running expected to know what to do it
won't know what to do
so you have to create meter this case it
has been created for us
so let's go ahead and start typing code
inside
so we can start by typing console they
can see that there's a window that pops
up right here
now it has about a where is it here that
you may or may not know what they do
now with this is called is his car into
Houston's
is what most helpful things that has
built a GUID
the looks at what you party written
gives suggestions based on that
so you can see here that the first one
is consul
which is what we want so what's next
type consul dot
they will do right acres here there is
that right can write my
was a row down and so it's right by
press tab
are back in style boris now
week alright my this is a said and
inside it inside at these for this is
right here
is what's called arguments now the
arguments for writing allied to the
console
is a string what a string is is it's a
budget characters put together
they're stored inside a have to
quotation marks so this type hello world
now this is our hello world string
it is not stored as a variable or a data
type
it's just there's for the time when the
in its gone now
it something just discard a literal
string
I don't know if it's the same Visual
Basic have that but I apps could cause a
little strip
a literal string because the same thing
so
down below that we're gonna have to do
is type consoles
dot read line and will leave
empty arguments for that because we
don't have to tell it to do anything
specific
now we come up here
you can see the start debugging hairy a
row but this does
is a it runs a program and debug mode
which will show us the air stand air
this so you can
clicked this or you can just press a 5
they can see that is star save a console
window
or a cmd window if that's too that's
what you might call it
and it says hello world you can see that
it stopped right here it is
stopping to let us read the line that's
why we called consul top Rehbein
now if we take out this line of code
and run it yes the
the window is going to pop up in a
disappearing fast
you know that over time
so
in order for us to be able to see what's
actually going on before close
gonna have to do canceled at redline we
run this
you CSS hello world so congratulations
guys you've successfully created your
first hello world program
and I stay tuned for the next tutorial
and extortion
don't forget to comment like and
subscribe