hello youtube same here from you to duck
house
on that Gaber this tutorial we'll be
taking a look at primitive data types
now what these are is pretty much the
building blocks have all the programs
you gonna bake
now I brokenness down in several
different categories sorry the top
we have primitive data types this is
divided into three more subsections
we've got numbers characters and logical
now under the numbers category we have
integers now this is all members that
aunt decibel
don't have decibels we have bite
which is a very small digit number that
can hold a value
starting at -120 a all the way up to
posit 127
now if you go past that well has
happened is called overflow and you will
get an airing the program
we've got the sort data type right here
which
is a sixteen-bit type it has a value
decade spent from negative 32768
all the way up to $32767
now we have the int type
for the integers now this is the type
that we're going to be easy most the
time
most the time in our tutorials because
we don't need to use by
short the we must because we don't have
to conserve resources we're not making
programs that are so big that we need to
use these
to conserve the pro to to serve the
resources and
int is just big enough rest use
and dad we will NEVER go outside the
Rams at that and
int data type is 32-bit and it can have
a beautiful
value native two billion $147 billion
480 3,680 for
and maximum value is $2 billion 147,000
483 I'm two billion $1.47 billion
for nearly three thousand 647 and over
here we have
long now at long is is its very much
7 sponsor is a lot integer it's a 64-bit
type and he can have a maximum value
the on Etsy 9
this the 9
workers at two trillion hold on here
that the maximum value and that long
is 9 quintillion 223 quadrillion
372 trillion $36 billion
$854 million 775,000
807 and the minimum value that
is pretty much that negative but said
any with 808
the here 807 into 808 now there are
other data types
in is a basic that I'm not gonna cover
in this
such as BigInteger which is something
that has been added the dotnet framework
4.0
and from what I've read about it and it
does not have a limit
so I'll Giuffrida player out that if you
could buy some places online
I will show you how to use that and now
moving on we have
real numbers now are real numbers are is
out anything that could hold a decimal
value
now we have double and float now double
is a 64-bit that type Anakin holds
with see term it's a 734 firm in point
which may not be missed you but
with that basically means is that you
can hold he really long decibel
and a float is a very the double
it's a quite similar and now moving on
to characters
we have what's called a character which
will hold
one characters such as the letter A or
the letter T or G
it is also one of those and now one
thing I did the list that
isn't technically a primitive data types
but I am I thought that
I strategic assessment in this tutorial
is a string
as pretty much a bunch of characters put
together he saw this in hello world
tutorial its enclosed into quotes
and it can hold as many characters as
you want and spaces and other stuff and
now
last but not least we have a logical
ideological we have to lean
bullying is a doubt type that can hold a
valuable
true or boss now you find this very
useful when you start making programs
so take a look at this chart make sure
you tomorrow this will be working with
these data types coming up in the next
two wheels
stay tuned for the next one don't forget
to comment like and subscribe