hell YouTube same from you should %uh
how such on that game here for New
Boston
and this is your we'll be taking a look
at comments your comments are very
useful the program's
and I'm its good practice to use them a
lot would be making beer programs
so that other people that you may be
working with on your project kid
region code understand or so that you
can also reach occurred and understand
to see you go back in the forget well
what was this deal was disconnected to
I'll when the common to hear tell me
what this does
says go ahead and create a new project
we disliked a console application
could call this comment click OK
it will load our project
let's go ahead and create that hello a
problem that were made in the last 20
BB
he is don't get it right now I think
there we are
this go ahead and you console
dot right by
hello world
the console dot read
line okay so now it's at some comments
today so anybody rigby this will know
what's going on
so do this you start by adding a
quotation double course just single
quotes
and anything it happen that line is the
party the comment
so we'll just say this
mind rights the text
hello world to the council
now down here below this
type this lines Paz's
the program and let's the user read
the text now if we go ahead run this
you can see the Comets don't effect
occurred anyway now when you compile
your program
comments always ignored by the compiler
so is white space at this why special
here we can add as much white space as
we want and is still going to read the
same
you can also add multi-line comments
and he won't affect your program at all
so test
you need to go ahead and read this it's
going to say
hello world you can also add comments
two lines of code
that don't have common sense themselves
such as this cancelled outright mind
statement right here I can add a Comment
add to that
that says hello
world is a literal string
and it won't affect program at all and
if we go up here
read this is getting come out I'm Visual
Basic
also has a builtin to a bar option
appear me earlier this year quit the let
you comment
out lines of code so it's a we want to
convert this out
begins come up here a quick comment out
the selected lines
well with you control K and then to
chill
see and it will effectively coming up
his mind
and so now if we go ahead and run the
program you can see the program in spy
art does is less read aloud it doesn't
actually print out hello world
and out on top with them
you just highlight what you want on
comment come up here
and click this you know and company
comment it for you I can also do right
here and if we run this
you see that classes open your fast then
closes