hello youtube same from you to dot com
slash
on that game here for the New Boston in
this tutorial we'll be talking about
airs a good to hear that the project we
had opened the last 20
so in Visual Basic and
a lot mostly are other programming
languages you got three types appears
yes syntax errors you got your runtime
errors
and get your logic errors now I'll take
you through
these three types airs and then I'll
show you how to use the airless down
here
with airs warnings and messages so
appears we have a program and sit at a
%uh the code correctly
if we run it is going to open up and
runs perfectly fine
is gonna put out hello world this is an
example
a program that has no airs and now want
to do is a mini create there
this as can be said tax air so you can
see
that when I type when I remove this
print disease here existing air down
here in the
airless it tells us X expression
expected
it has the power it said so over you
know Solution Explorer
we've got our comments project got my
projects within
wittoled other settings and set for it
we got are filed module 1.0 BB
now projects you have a whole bunch
about you know a buncha bottles about
two classes
or forbes and other stuff so
this is very useful when you make bigger
programs does ill let you know
which file in it'd it also lets you know
which slide it is
and that is why we che we show the lines
by coming up here
to go to tools options text editor
general all languages and
click checked line numbers now we did
that so that
whenever we get airs we can see the
wider but that's it here
come over to our file and we could
come down here to identify where it is
college 26 now called 26 just means that
it is
16 spaces over for the left
right here they see that whenever you
have a syntax air
it's got a little squiggly line under it
just let you know it is
now if we go ahead and try to read this
it won't run in to say that
there were built airs ever go ahead
Texas it should run perfectly fine it
says another world right there
and now let's go ahead and talk a little
bit about runtime: airs
I can say example the runtime area
simple program like this
but I'll try to explain to you as best I
can now see you making
a I an FTP dollar which is what we're
going to make
later I'd the close the in the tutorials
what we covered everything I'm teach you
how to build specific programs
and I'm a ticket to the steps I used to
builders
so that they were creating an FTP
download we would open a file
to uploaded to the FTP server
so we try to open a file and it works
fine
and the ones which are uploaded to the
server its gonna give us a air because
say the user doesn't have access to that
now because the user doesn't have
write permissions when they try to
upload it is gonna give the
air the program's going to freeze up as
can stop working and
you had force close it so basically what
you need to do
to handle this is to you go ahead
and in close all that cause it was
college try catch statement
now what this does is it ties about good
catches in the areas that are thrown
ended want to catch those decides what
to do with them
now all the programs that we're going to
be riding or those muscle
over to the cause in we not gonna need
it I catch statements so will be learned
that later on
so that's pretty much what
a runtime: areas now I'll tell you what
a
logic area is a logic air is something
debt most the every programmer hates
what it means is that you program to
pass by erodes find
but then the results for the outcome
that you get from using a program is not
what you expected
so others too
an example a logic here this will be
really simple logic here
so say I forget to the Dukan so that
really bad
and when I read this it just flashes
encloses really quick
so that's just a a basic
logic here but an example
have a major allies would be let's say
somebody makes a calculator and they
build on these classes for it
and it went to go the calculated values
it the calculations are wrong
and that makes it really hard because it
doesn't tell you where the heirs are
because they're taking the day is it air
this is an area in what you did
and the outcome is not what you expected
so the doubt that covered the
three types of hairs we could not hear
and taken
closer look at a realist now you see
that we have 0 errors
in 0 warnings now in a warning is
is pretty much the compiler trying to
protect you from
areas possibly happening when you run
your code so it's a
me understand this let's say you create
it very well
and the variable is dole and
you try to do something but the the
variable is never signed
the jar call that variable you gonna get
no and you gonna get
and airs that so always
always look at your warnings don't
ignore them and I'm
other messages it's just gives the
possible things
that you may well okay so that you
taking a look at some of the heirs
an airtight you can get anybody today
released and how to
find those errors and fix them and go
ahead and
just play around a little bit more maybe
washes again just to get that stuck in
your head
and I was done with that go ahead and
move on to the next tutorial and don't
forget to comment like and subscribe