hello youtube Sam from you to dot com
slash
on I came here for the New Boston in
this tutorial
will be talked about variables now
variables are the most important parts a
programming
there's no possible way to make a
program without variables
so understood started and will create a
variable here
now to create a variable in Visual Basic
you can start off with the keyword
diem now what this tells the compiler is
that you're going to declare
a variable so you read this
right here from intelligent says that
the dim statement declares and allocates
here declares allocates new storage
space for one or more variables
so or gonna do israeli type did
it after this you can type whatever name
you want as long as it contains bad
characters
now as those that you could buy it was
about characters
online or invalid characters some was
just %ah
by calling it by them he condemned this
whatever you feel like
and now after we tell the compiler
I'll what the neighbors are variables
gonna be we're gonna type
has services says specifies the data
type in the Dec
declaration statements that was gonna
tell the compiler what kinda data type
is gonna be
as a way to make ours and integer and so
you can see that little green line comes
into that
and is a warning here says a news local
variable not
by now so would have a kid programs
if you never use a variable the careless
is going to tell you the warning so that
you can take that out
the program more efficient or using my
dance or just ignore that
warning for right now so now we're going
to do is win a signed by
sort i mind equals by
now if we do cancel
dot right line
my nom and they'll do console dot
read line we go ahead run this
its gonna say 5 right there
now what we can do is wicked
instead of putting this into lines we
can go ahead and set the value
are variable in the declaration I'm
so it is a sequel to 5 there now the
reason I showed you
the 2i bet they'd before that is because
sometimes you to be declaring a variable
wanna be ourselves and later on he said
she gonna be a sign that another value
now that would be
a way you wouldn't do that so for
example
if I read this good read this you know
say
5 now come down here
set minor equal to something else such
as seven
to go and read this is going to print
out seven
because even though we decide lies my
debit 5
after we do that its gonna re
its gonna change the value my dad 27 and
its gonna write the
most recent value by them now doesn't
save the old values it just updated
so it's gonna start at five which ended
7 and it prints out the seven which is
the what it's completely equal to
so let's go ahead and
work with a another time QB Taylor
I want to not caps lock tap okay
says go ahead and get rid of my
government here and will the Clearstream
sodium my string as
string and we're going to set it equal
to hello
do Boston
sands so now if we come back here
and we've cancelled outright mine we're
just gonna put my string
as the arguments and you can see that it
prints out
hello the New Boston fans now if you
wanna do a character
we can just do Tim my
character as Carey Rs
char elsa equal to a for him a
every type out my
character you can see that in Oprah now
a for us now let's go ahead and do
a double really quick simply to double
the Eagle said Eagle 25.4 go-ahead run
this
your say 5.4 for us now this work with
able in real quick
would create a bullied variable said
equal to you either true or false so so
you go to
and will pronounce my character
or hear those changes to my
pool
now you can see here that it prints out
true now can also set this to
false if we
run this is going to bring up false now
here's something that I was going to
teach you guys in a related to real
but I figured that you guys a smart so
I'll go and teach it to you in this
tutorial now whenever you
create in a variable and let's just do
escape integer now said he qualified
what we want to do is in our Casa not
right line
what we want to take mine and we want to
convert it
to a string now you may not notice any
difference
any differences in this but I'll I was
taught
that whenever you its good coding
practice to convert
numbers two strings when you gonna be
printing about anywhere on the screen
such as the label
or text box or console which is what
we're we are working in
so to convert a string you just do the
variable that you want
dot to string with empty parameters
in this is going to convert your integer
to string now clear on this
you can see it puts out by but instead
of putting out a number this is actually
a string
so
that's about all I will recover in the
variables tutorial
so I'm passes and variables I'm
make some your own printing out and get
used to what they are
and then once you've got that now down
move on to the next tutorial and don't
forget to comment like and subscribe