hello youtube
same from you to die com slash OnLive
game here
for the New Boston in this tutorial
we'll be taking a look
at simple math operators so that's good
decided
we're gonna come up here into our code
I'm going to start off by declaring a
variable
now we're gonna make it integer so do II
as integer will go ahead and said that
he qualified
or here was not that said that he could
anything yet
so did not mind equals side
plus by snafu come down here
and print out number one on the console
it's going to give us the output 10
where we can also do
is used the parameters a bright line
cue add numbers 2.1 so we're be by this
is that say we have no blood we want to
print out dumb one
plus 5 so we read this
we should get 15 now if we come here
we can also subtract five so nobody
conspired -5
that's going to give us the value of 0
and now
we print that out it's going to take
this out we put that up
here we get 0 we can also do
division so to divide is a basic
this is the same throughout mostly all
languages you use the forward slash
so if we divide time by 5 we're going to
get the value
wide and to multiply
use use the asterisk so fight outside
is equal to 25 right there
and now we can also do
the powers so 5 to power
to is going to equal 25
every five to the power 3
we're gonna get what is 125 so here we
go 125 right there
now what we can also do
is what's called module is now this is a
little
to keep for some people to understand
about how to explain it the best I can
well by julos does is it will divide two
integers for you
and they give you the remainder so if we
do five
mod to so so what happens when you bite
by bite you
you can get to with the remainder have
one as his reason it is we can't get
decibel so we're going to get a
remainder
so now if we run this you can see that
it prints out
one we can also
at variables to each other so
if we declared them one as integer and
we said equal to 4
we can declare second variable scholars
on
to okay did Jer and we'll set it equal
to
8 it now if we print out
number one place no
to is gonna give us the value have
12 this also works
for all the other operators that we've
seen we can multiply them together
which will give us the value 32 and what
we can do
is written create a third able here
let's just do that
creative able to answer on
make it integer you know said equal to
or personal said equal to
nothing basically what nothing is is if
you've learned
any other languages its equivalent to
dole so
answer instead a not assigning answer
value
was himself equal than nothing you can
see that
it won't give us a a warning here so
if we take this out we get a warning
but since we assign it to nothing
which is equivalent to no we don't get
one here and that will
prevent airs from possibly happen in the
future so that down here
was typed answer equals
no mind divided by them
to now in our case in this program we
didn't have to
set is equal to nothing that's when
mister that in there so you guys and
know what it is
be able to use a weight on your programs
so answer equals
number one divided by dumped you so
if we right out answer
we are going to get 0
so if you for divided by
8 you get a decimal number
and since integers can't can't
im they can implicitly convert
themselves to
decibels is just gonna give you zero so
let's go ahead and change this to you
multiply
and we're going to get 32
now since before we got zero by dividing
them
by two other I'm William a show you how
to fix this
what we're gonna do instead of making
the integers
we're gonna make them doubles here
we don't have to make those doubles we
can make the answer
a double so
now since I answer can have decimal
numbers if we divide number my name to
we will get 0.5
so take a look at some these math
operators and play around them with
doubles integers you can use a by you
can use along can is
anything just play around with his math
operators get used to them
in what you got that down go ahead and
move on to the next tutorial
and thanks for watching don't forget to
comment like and subscribe