hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash
on my game up for the new bassam and its
oil we're going to take another look at
math operators and some other things
they can do with it
and stuff that I went down last tutorial
so it's good decided
here's our mains are right here server
module which can start by creating a
variable
so we'll use the dim key word to say
they were gonna creative able
will give it a name which is my double
in ways that add
as keyword which tells the compiler that
were about
tell it what kinda data we want to use
and which to
double and said equal to 11
now a new console died
right mind my double
where this is going to do is is just
gonna print out the value
11 now if we come down here
and change the value my double with him
I double
equals my double plus
23 they will do consul
died right line my double
now we run this we're gonna get the
values
11 and 34 but if we just take this right
now right here
and copy this
okay so we take design are here
and add the plus 23 into the arguments
the consul that right mind where this is
going to do is is gonna bring a 11 at 34
but the value of my double isn't
actually changed Sophie
right out consul dot right line
my double again we're gonna get the
values
11 34 in 11 because we never change the
variable
it's the right there is now or gonna do
is I'm recover a bit sure had met so
here that's type my double
equals my double plus
23 which is what we just did now there's
easier way to do this
whenever you wanna at a value to very
but they have
are you have to do is do this scum this
out
with you my double plus
equals 23 so this does the empire that
we want to take the variable my double
we went at the value 23 to it enough
weed spread out again
we're going to get the value 11 in 34
let's go ahead and make a
sure they're simple program here it's
going to take a very well estimate track
it throughout the changes that we made
so let's take this line out right here
and what we're gonna do is we're going
to use Ustream
inside arguments cancelled outright
right so tight
initial value
and it will type new value and now to
combine these two together
which can be used the and sign so what
this does
is it takes a string that we've made in
the
at my double to it where this is going
to do is on the console
we're gonna see is this these letters
right here
its gonna say initial value 11 you value
11 buses we don't know what the new guy
is going to be
words can use the ensign print out my
double which changes
whenever we changes to the program and
we don't have to know
specific specifically what its equal to
you so
modest copy this string right here
and will do one more action go ahead and
do my double
times equals 126
now whenever you do this right here you
can use it with any other matter
operator you can divide you can subtract
you can multiply
you can add whenever you want so as Duke
on so that right line
and they will take this right here
were added arguments
in the open out my double with it so now
if we run this
we're gonna get initial value 11
which is the initial value my double the
new value is 11
because we hadn't changed it yet the
code and in
in the wind down below that to say
initial value 11 new value
34 in below that again is can say
initial by 11 you value
for that into an 84 so that is a simple
program now jacki Perry movie make
changes to it
and if you have any questions feel free
to comment them
I'm I will be margin is BS and I thanks
for watchin
stay tuned for the next tutorial