hell YouTube same here from you to dot
com slash
on live gamer for the New Boston and the
situation will be talking about getting
user input from the Consul
now this is very useful when you can
console applications
because what's the point in making an
application
if the user can it imply anything so
it's going to get started
go ahead aid creator Bob variables here
so use diem wishes to you
user name as string I'll start off by
setting
setting equal to nothing now this is
just
a safety precautions here because if the
user
does not input anything as they re
name did stream would not be equal to a
value
and we're getting a reef which I print
that out on the console
says go ahead and clear another
value so user age as integer
in said that people are nothing just in
case they don't imply anything
because they will get an area of which I
print out something that's not equal to
anything
so they will do diem
users salary has
double I'll go ahead and take that
said that equal to nothing as well so
now what we're going to do you
is real prompt the user to input some
information
soul just create a string it out over
arguments
and will type what is your name
now we want to do
is ruining it wait for them to you
I'm putting their name so what we gonna
do
to do this is going to type username
equals consul
dot read lines so what this does
is whenever the user types in
a string of characters and presses enter
its gonna read that by Darren story in
the variable username
the wicked go I'm
and prompted to type something else so
the console dot
right line what
is your age and it will type
user age equals
time so dot read by
and we'll just do that again and get
their salary civil type
console dot right line
what is yours salary
and we use disappear again
to get their salary from the council so
tight user
salary equals console died
read line
snap a good run this
you see is going to say what is your
name it's about have been Sam
press Enter what it does is its stores
same
in stride inside username him free
typing aids sauce a 15
out at my salary so it's a
I know I am a millionaire's so five
hundred dollars
our for 550 insisted that and I
see it didn't do anything so we
basically did
was we prompted the user to type in
something
it we got that from the console and
historian username
but we need to do something with using
so we're gonna do
is we're going to print that out
so to cancel dot right line
you make
or hola
your name is and they will just add
their name
so user name as go ahead and take
outlined here
and they will do
console dot right shit at a space your
core spaces
you were age is it will just
add user age in console that right again
your salary is
okay so what this test is it's going to
you
right out your name is but he says
instead of using right mind we use right
so what this does is once it's done
writing this text right here is not
gonna go down to the next line
and its gonna pre your age is on the
same minus that is can also bring your
salary is
on the same ones that so then this go
ahead
and just you consul dot right mind
to go ahead in the wind so that we can
read
what's on the Consul his go-ahead run
this
say what is your name I type in same
say what is your age I did fifteen was
your salary
five hundred dollars and fifty cents an
hour you know say
your name is Sam you were ages 15 the
salary is 505
now whenever you type in a
a number value into the Consul so sad
type in five hundred-point 50
0 is not needed so it is taken out when
I print that
so say I typed 00 500
it's gonna take that I just gimme five
hundred now I'll give you an example
this
socket type you say what is your name
types ambush a I type 000 15
what is your salary as 000
miss you eight dollars time eight
dollars 34 cents an hour
say your name is Sam you were ages 15
and your salary is 834
so what this does is it takes out all
the unnecessary
zeros in there because 0000 or however
many zeros are
15 is just equal to the value 15
so Visual Basic is going to take out the
zeros for E
you could if you wanted to you could
change that to a string
and it would print out all these numbers
together and not take out those zeros
if you want to so I'm extorted
and stay tuned for the next tutorial