hello to you too same here from YouTube
dot com slash
on live gamer for the New Boston and in
this tutorial
we're going to be using some of the
things that you've learned in the last
tutorial
to make a simple calculator program says
go ahead and get started
we go ahead and kisses FaceTime herein
are made said
ever going to prompt the user to input a
value so use consul
dot right mind please
inter the first number now what we're
going to do
is we're going to declare a variable and
we use
canceled at redline to store the
information in that variable
so is that the did keyword so
damn number one as
double and woody said equal to you
console dot read line
so if you want to read a value from the
line
or if you want to get the input to the
user's putting in you can declare the
variable
inside to conserve battery died at the
same time you can do all this the one
mine which saves you some
coating time so now we have a first
number
we're gonna do use consul
die right mind I was gonna tell the user
what that person a breeze they know that
the program received it correctly
so do first member
in which issues the inside
and will print out no one now or gonna
do is really prompted to enter a second
number
so we will use consul
dot right mind please
into the second number
now we're going to create another
variable so we will use it in keyword
will do diem no to as
double and we'll set it equal to you
console dot redline so this does the
same thing that we did up here
in declaring number one and we use
concert I read 9
in itself the more that you were going
with them to you okay
so now we're going to print out the
answer the first woman tell them
that we receive their first
democratically so
cancelled outright line second number
now we're going to create
a third variable with we will delete
and will type answer as the name
we want to make it a double and we'll
set it equal to
number one times
no to you now is gonna print that out
so console dot right mind
answer
also the equal to answer
over at answer to that and we do use the
and sign right here now who run this
program
you know say please enter the first
number
supply type: 32 press ENTER its gonna
tell me the first number is 32
is going to ask before the second number
so as to forty-five
NEC close on its right there
so we need to add consul dot redline
okay so into the first number
34 he says person under 34
and well into the second number 45 we
present a real tell us the second number
you know tell us the answer so that's
good to hear
and less just specify what the
calculated
so do the numbers multiplied
is is going to give us the answer now
what we can do to save time
is we can get rid of answer all by
itself
instead of putting up pretty out the
answer
we can do number one times
dime to so what this does
is it takes an armored about the prized
by them to only does that
arguments of counsel that right nine so
is nice or as a variable
it is going to print out that number and
is not going to save anywhere
now you can choose which one you want to
do if you want to use answer later on
then I would suggest declaring that
variable
and storing in there because if you want
to answer later on
and you didn't declare a variable for it
you will be able to get the answer
because
the only time that you have the answer
printed out the screen or stored
anywhere
is with you writes this line and
multiply them together
so you had play around the
you can make it not by you can make a
divide you can make your ad
whenever you want and what you've got
and no doubt move on to the next
tutorial