hello youtube same here from YouTube dot
com slash
OnLive gaming for the New Boston and
this tutorial
we're gonna be wearing the if statement
now the if statement
is one of the most useful tools for
beginners
in Visual Basic because there's so much
that you could do with it
is very easy to pick up is very
intuitive says go ahead get started
the first up we are going to make a
program
that we're asking users for their
username and password
this may be a little bit different than
what you'd expect for a username
password login to be
bud it will give you the concept the if
statement and that you'll be able to go
make some programs using the if
statement and get used to it so that you
can move on to the next tutorials
so is going to get started with a
console
dot right mind what is
your name now or gonna do
is we're going to declare Street so used
to did he were to let
Visual Basic know that we're going to
make a very able so
will DM username as
string and we'll set it equal to cart so
dot read line now or gonna do
is really do console
da right line which can ask them for
their password
so white is your
password in will declare another
variable
and it'll be password so damn password
as a string we're going to equal to
consul dot redline
soldiers getting whatever the user type
did so now we're gonna create
are if statement so to start off in a
statement using use the keyword
yes wheat added it's going to highlight
it blew its gonna showed up in
intellisense
now the the definition for the if
statement this is
conditionally conditionally excuse a
group statements depending on the value
of an expression
so basically what that says is is a
certain
I condition is true the go ahead and do
whatever is inside this
if statement so is username
equals same did what we wanted to do
and if you press enter you can see there
are automatically add
in if for you olives Davis have in
within in if or else you'll get a syntax
error
so do if using a pic of sam
then consul dot right
line welcome Sam
in our dish can you create a second its
statement so if password
equals the New Boston
did well what we wanted to do
we will just type consul dot
right line insider there
what type you have enter the correct
password
okay so now if we run this you see we
have a little bit of a problem here
so we type what is your name that axiom
what is your password
the New Boston his era close out right
after we're done with that
so which can add a redline right here
so consul dot read
line its initial deposit program
and let us see you what we have done so
what is your name
same and what is your password the New
Boston
so because name is equal to Sam
is going to bring out welcome Sam and
because
the new boss in the past so that we have
typed in is equal to
the New Boston in our code right here
its gonna say
you enter the correct password so
let's go ahead and with separate this a
bit here just to make the
over it a little bit more readable so
we'll just
write another line which is just give us
a blank line in separate these
self-awareness again say what is your
name and if I type
said Gerald and say what is a pastor at
had the New Boston
is going to say you have enter the
correct password
but didn't say welcome Sam because
gerald
is not equal to Sam so username
whatever they have tidied is jailed and
is not able to say I am so it will not
do the coincided here
and suit since we typed in the New
Boston as a password
it's going to tell us that we have into
the crack password
and it's also work the other way around
so if we do
what is your name Sam and say what is
your password
assay OnLive gaming ivs say welcome Sam
but it won't tell us that we have into
the correct password
so here
is basic example the if statement
they're very fun to use when you first
begin programming
you can do a lot with them a lot more
than that you think you could and I so
go ahead
look at this coat over again go ahead
and use a in statements and make some
programs yourself
and what you got if there is no doubt go
ahead and move on to the next tutorial