hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash
on I came in for the New Boston and this
tutorial
organ becoming the else if else
statement so the last 20
we covered the if statement now this go
ahead and get started
we're gonna start of by
using cancelled outright by and we'll
just type
what is your name
now we're going to create a variable
call username ever getting store the
information that a user types in
as username so declare using sodium
username as string
and what city equal to you consul dot
read
line now we want to do
is what I asked him for the password so
will just type cancelled I right mind
what is your password
and will declare the password
SODIMM password as string as
equal to you consul dot redline
okay so now we want to do is we want to
create an if statement
see if they typed in and name that is in
let's say
a list the possible names that can be
logged in so is username
equals same
or that same said that same same
dead do something so if username
is equal the same they will do console
died
right mind welcome same
now we want to cover any other cases
that could happen now I could do this
with a budget is statements that's not
very efficient
we can use what's called in else if
statement so
we just do this but having else's
username
equals Tim so views may be caused him
if we want to do something so
will decide console dodd right
line welcomed him
so basically basically what we've done
is if user name is equal to Sam
go ahead and say welcome same but if you
use an ABC quality and
it's a welcome Tim and this is all in
one a statement by using
else it in case somebody else tries to
log in and we don't know who they are
which can tell them that they have
tightening down name
now to do this we're gonna type
else so else
go ahead and do the code that is inside
in between else in India
what else does is it covers anything
else that you did not cover
so it is an equal say in this can go
ahead do this
but else if use in the people's ten you
know do this infusion Eagles
anything else other than to him or to
him the go-ahead
and do whatever we tied inside here
soldiers type consul
died right line you are not
a valid user added after in if
we'll just do consul dot redline
said so that the user has time to
see if they've been accepted receive
that have been the right name
so if we do what is your name night I
pinned Sam
just a what is your password are just
type in
the New Boston you know say welcome Sam
and then it won't say anything else
after that because we haven't added
anything that will handle the password
so now here and there again
your say what is your name what I did
10 or see
this is case sensitive so Tim
and say what is your password I've been
about stuff right there
says welcomed him now type anything else
other that same or 10 its gon say
you are not a valid user so we can do
the same thing
with our I'm password so
if password equals
the New Boston then
go ahead and let the user know that they
have been granted access
so will decide console dot
right line and will say
congratz and then we'll just add their
usernames so
congratz username and they will say
you have been
granted access now
this is a very secure but is just for
the sake this tutorial I say
instead if you are not a valid user as
you say
I don't know who you are so that way
the person doesn't have to have the
right username but if they have the
I say the administrator password they
can go ahead and login
so I don't know who you are so we go
into this
say what is your name let's just say
same
what is your password typed in New
Boston
to say welcome Sam graduation same you
have been granted access
now all we need to do he is
as space right here so that Sam is right
next to that
so now if we type an invalid username
you know say should do this
in for type in the New Boston you see
that will
get out the I don't know you are you
know say congrat
a Dafa you have been granted access so
go ahead and practice some else if
statements and smell statements
get familiar with that and then once you
that no doubt go ahead and move on to
the next tutorial