hello youtube same here from YouTube dot
com slash
on I came in for the New Boston in this
tutorial
we're gonna be taking a look at nested
if statements now the last tutorial we
covered
else if statements and else it now if
you don't know if they've been is I
would suggest you move our backs on
about early
earlier tutorials and learn from that
no and what you know if statement is go
ahead and move on to this tutorial
so basically what a nested if statement
is
is that you take one if statement it you
put another if statement cited this
and what that does is it makes it where
both values have to be true
for the condition for the program inside
the in a loop
to run so I let's go ahead and create
a little example this so you go ahead
and declare a variable and this variable
is going to be there age
sodium age as integer
and we'll set it equal than nothing so
just in case they don't type anything we
wanted
air we try to print out there age now
we're going to
create insurance so in new DM
has insurance as
bully ever you go ahead and said that he
courted nothing
to so now we're going to do
is green asked him what the ages so do
console
to right line what is
your age now which you can set the
vary by age to whatever they type in so
age equals console da redline now we're
gonna ask him
if they have insurance so will do
consul dot right by do you have
insurance
true
or false and will do
has insurance equals console dot
read line now this will not work if that
had anything other than sure foss
your program will get an area and it
will crash this is just for the sake of
it it over
tutorial now we're going to create our
if statement so
is age equals
16 did we want do whatever is inside
this
statement now we're gonna create and his
team inside this which is called the
nested if statement so if has
insurance equals
true there we want to do the code inside
this
will just type console dot right line
you can drive
legally
now or gonna do is weakening cover the
case
them not have insurance so we're just
gonna go ahead and tight
else so if age is equal to 16 it has
insurance is equal to false
because the only other option we have
for has insurance is false
we're gonna type consul dot right mind
you can drive but don't get pulled over
or you are screwed
okay so now we run this its gonna go
ahead and say
what is your age so what type in 16
and say do you have insurance true or
false suffice it true
its gonna say you can drive don't is a
in say you can drive legally they can
see that it closed out
right after we did that soldiers console
that read by
say gives us time to read that before we
can close the program
and say what is your age
sauce a sixteen and I do have insurance
so to say you can drive legally now
if I type in 16 for age
and false for do you have insurance
say you can drive for don't get pulled
over or you're screwed
and now at my age
is not equal to 16 let's say 12
yes I do you have insurance you are
false
I say fast it's not going to say
anything because
the first value was not you so it won't
move on to the next yr
inside the nested loop so what we're
gonna do
Israel had a simple else right here so
if ages ago 16 the do the stuff in here
and else
cancelled I right line you cannot drive
would happen twelve-year
in type in all
you know say you cannot try now
there is a better way to do this by
using what's called
conditional operators and logical
operators
I wanted you guys I wanted to teach you
guys have to make nested
if statements and unacceptable tutorials
we'll be learning conditional operators
and the use for this is that
age has to be equal to 16 and if there
are any older than 16
did it won't work so I said 21 they can
legally drive
but it says you cannot drive so the way
to get around this is to use
conditional operators so
makes unless it is statements and keys
to them
and what you've got is now that go ahead
move on to the next tutorial