hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash
on my gamer for the New Boston in this
tutorial we'll be covering
conditional operators now basically
we're conditional operators are
is testing the sea if that value is
either less than
greater than less than or equal to
greater than or equal to or not equal to
you another value
so let's go ahead and get started we're
gonna go ahead and create a couple
variables appear
so will create a variable called
is in kindergarten as Billy
and was go ahead and said they could do
nothing now we're going to create
a couple other balloons and now the
reason we're doing this
is because we're gonna see and will use
the person's age determined
different things that they can and can't
do or
whether there at a certain point in
their life so
now gonna do Tim candid
drink as billion and you had said that
when he called I think to
and will diem and
is a or is senior citizen
as bullied
it was said that when he called nothing
to ok is now we're going to do
is going to prompt the user to put in
their name saw type
console dot right line or not their name
their age
what is your age now we're going to
create a new variable that stores your
age
sodium a jazz integer
ever said equal to consul to
redline so whatever they type in his
story in The
age variable so now we're going to
create some if statements here
so is
if
age does not equal 5 then do this
so basically that not equals operator
in Visual Basic is the less than sign
and the greater than sign
right next to each other now if you use
to any other languages
sometimes they were use the exclamation
mark
equals but in Visual Basic it's just
like that
so it age is not equal to 5% the week
we're gonna go ahead and set
is in kindergarten equal to false and
now
if it's anything else or if it is a
qualified
the is in kindergarten is equal to true
so now
we are going to create another statement
so
if age is greater than
or equal to 65 then
we're going to say that they are a
senior citizen so
is senior citizen equals
true and now at the age
is anything else that's not greater than
or equal to 65 which
pretty much set that's lower than 65
then
is senior citizen is going to be said
equal to you false
is an hour going to come down here below
that
and will make another
statement so if age
greater than or equal to you
21 then
can drink
is equal to you true
and
else can drink is equal to false
so now we're gonna do
is since we have all these if statements
made
to set the value to the balloons gonna
go ahead and create
a string so will do
damn outcome as
stream I'll go ahead and set the equal
to nothing or the issue
outcome kindergarten now is go ahead and
make a couple more these
and let's do
outcome senior
and outcome during
now are what we're gonna do is it age is
not a qualified
then outcome kindergarten
equals you aren't in
kindergarten
and that's just go ahead and copy this
right here
and if day are in kindergarten
which can tell them you are in
kindergarten now
outcome senior
equals you are a senior or citizen
your senior citizen and if they are
younger than 65 they were going to tell
them that they aren't
and now
outcome drink equals you
can drink because is greater than or
equal to 21
the Kendrick is equally true it's it's
Kendrick is a good true
they were going to say that they can do
it and now
else we're gonna say you cannot drink
now or gonna do
after all this is done we're going to
console
dot right mind outcome
drink and outcome
kindergarten and outcome
senior now is go ahead and add a couple
spaces in here
so outta space right there between as
just make are outcome with a little bit
nicer
so that their spaces in between each one
if the message is that we have here
okay so now if we run this hopefully
everything works I'm
if you type in what is your age okay
there we go we got a problem right there
I housing to do this in the program's
we're gonna have to add a consul that
remind okay
soon after we run this you say what is
your age
in every type in five in say you cannot
drink you are in kindergarten
in the art a senior citizen and now if
we do something
like 21 say you can drink
you are dick in your garden and you are
a senior citizen and now it is one more
time
say what is your age will be sixty-seven
USA
you can drink you are in kindergarten
and you are a senior citizen
so make a couple programs
and using these conditional operators
they're very useful when using if
statement and it was you got that no
doubt go ahead and move on to the next
tutorial