hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash
on life came in for the New Boston in
this tutorial we'll be taking a look at
logical operators
now basically a logical operators are is
that's a year using if statement so you
wanna do you
if this number is equal to a certain
value
or this number is equal to a different
the go ahead and do everything if
statement now
the or in that would be considered a
logical operator
you can also use the and operators so
let's say
if this number
is less than a certain value
and another number is less than a
certain value go ahead do whatever's in
Echo
so I'm let's go ahead and make a little
demo program for this
eyes could be similar to the log in one
third done before solace going to
stardom
we're gonna go ahead and declare our
username and password
sodium username as string
answer it with nothing in our gonna make
a password
so Tim password
as a stream we're going to set that
equal nothing to say just in case they
don't
type anything okay so now we're going to
do is going to prompt the user to enter
their username
soda right mind what
is your name now we want to do is worst
or their names of course
so username because time sold out
redline
now which can ask them for their
password so
will be cancelled outright by what is
your password
and with you
password equals console dot get mine
or die redline sorry okay so now that
with prompt the user to enter the name
and password we have stored both their
name in the password in variables
we want s those to see if we're going to
let the user in so we're going to start
off by creating an if statement
you type if username equals
same game go ahead
do this now or gonna do Israel at
in or operators who this now added or
operator
you gonna go ahead and just type the
keyword or
capital lower case are so if username
people seem
or username equals
10 now time 10
the go-ahead do this so let's go ahead
in print that out
so we can see what happens so cancelled
outright mind
hello anywhere just
add their username and they will go
ahead and cancel that read I'm
so we have time to read online before it
close okay to say what is your name
if I type in same ill say what is your
password I can't I do whatever I want
here
will say hello Sam now by type Tim
to say hello to him but about everything
else did nothing will show up
so now we want to do
is we won a test to see if the user name
is correct
or the password name it originated is
correct
and the password is correct so to do
this
missus go ahead and close this
in parentheses so this is going to be
its own separate
part the the if statement now this may
be a little confusing to you
but if you just go ahead practices after
this you understand it so
if his name because im or use an a
because team in the and operator is this
capital a
Indy you'll see that highlights to now
this is very simple
in other languages you got some symbols
for the and in or operator like the or
operator in C bus bus for example
will be that right there but in Visual
Basics is it sits at
a high-level language its the existing
this is very easy to
write code in the world best so if using
a beagle same
or username Eagles team and password
equals the New Boston
then we're gonna go ahead and tell them
that they have access by this
saying hello username basically what
this does is
is anything in here is true so
is this part issue and password it was
the New Boston issue so
if username people say missed you or use
any because Tim issue
in this whole part right here soon be
equal trip to true
and then and pass riegle's the New
Boston so this hope our last equal to
and password it was a new boston has
deport you
now this might be a little confusing to
you but I am just
this time try to figure out this again
if you have any questions in the comment
so if these Tuesday if these two
conditions are true:
the go ahead and let them in and ask go
ahead
and tied else will say cancelled
outright mine
access not granted
so if we run this program type what is
your name
bosses other say same you know type the
New Boston
it'll say hello Sam now scored once
again
and you can see their work with him to
you so
name is Tim password is the New Boston
you know say hello to him we've been
granted access
but anything is
not true so it's a we don't I P the same
or team so we tied
Joe and that which had to pass for the
New Boston
even though the password is correct is
gonna say access not going in
because to date has to be great it has
to be either Sam or Joe
and the password has to be good to the
New Boston
so on go ahead and practiced and make
some programs yourself with some
logical operators and once you've got a
logical operators now down
go ahead and move on to the next
tutorials and
thanks for watching