hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash
on live gamer for the New Boston ends
2/2
will be taking a look at what's called
concatenating strings
basically what this means is taking one
string
in adding another string to a and
when you do this is stored in another
variable says going to get started
we're going to create concatenate demo
so go ahead
got a new project we will name this
string concatenate and they will go
ahead and click
okay make sure you have selected a
consul application now here is my jewel
let's go ahead and zoom in here a bit
okay so now we're going to do
is we are going to create a string so
diem users sharing as stream
it will go ahead and said that you could
do nothing because we can have then type
in
a string now or gonna do
is we're going to create another string
that will be stored in our program
so im programs during
as stream and order said that it was
something right I'm
catfish now or gonna do
is real prompt the user to enter
industry so the console
dot right line type anything you want
so now we're going to do
is really get with a tight so users tree
equals
console dot redline now what we're gonna
do
is we're going to take their users chain
and add programs trying to it
so but first we're gonna print out with
a tight
so can so that right line users chain
an hour into Israel had programs chain
to it so
users chain equals
is chain plus
programs tree so basically what this
does
is it takes users chain in as program
shame to it
and makes all one word that's good
not one word one stream so it's good at
it a space in catfish so it will you
will be able to see the space in there
in or going to you is run a printout
users change
again and a modest
have the program pas away first to press
Enter
by using consul that read mine now or
just run it
endorse a type anything you want Sophie
type in
snowboarding go ahead and
press ENTER Irsay snowboarding in the
row se snowboarding which is what the
user entered
in the ads program showing to that now
we can you
is we can come back in here and we can
add
morse changed to this now the strange
don't have to be very because we can go
ahead and add
I'm anything we want by in closing in
quotes so this tie
I'm fishing
so now it's gonna do is going to take
what they typed
at catfish the add fishing now we can
also use this which is what we've used
in several other tutorials we can use
the ensign
inside a concert outright 9 statement to
add another string to it
so decide hello YouTube what this does
is it takes you string and as hell
YouTube to it for the time being
and then it doesn't save had hella
YouTube it's just there when this class
is not right on his car
and it disappears so let's go ahead and
run this
now to say type anything you want
substance am
it shows as well we originally typed
ssam
same catfish fishing hello youtube so
you can do this
anywhere you want you can even add
administering a here
and I'm
can get me as much as you want in the
string remember if you
use the ensign inside are you mister
talks about right line
this is going to be discarded as soon as
you're done with this statement or since
the programs that this statement
so and this is very simple concept
donated you guys that
and I'm it should be easy for you to
understand once you understand that
go ahead and move on to the next
tutorial