hello youtube Sam hear from you to dot
com size
on my game if the New Boston initiatory
we take another look at strings
now E look to change the last tutorial
after the next
couple up coming to us we are asking a
look at some other stuff that you can do
with strings
so let's go ahead and get started now it
come up here
and we're going to declare a variable so
let's go ahead
and im username
as string now or gonna do
is real prompt the user to enter in
their username soldiers to cancelled
outright line
what is
your username now username
is going to be equal to you console dot
redline so basically just get with eight
active now we're gonna do
is a unit test to see if the user name
is a certainly so is gonna make it
simple is saving
so if username in our gonna do is win at
a
period so if use named I
and you can see here the intellisense
pops up with a whole buncha stuff that
we can do
and you can copy you can
dudack contains there's a whole bunch of
stuff that you can use
I'm with strings in this is very usefull
so or what we're going to use is
username dot Lee now he read a
description for this
is gonna say gets the number of
characters
in the current system dusting object so
if username dot linked equals
10 did go ahead and do something
soldiers to console dot right line
you have been granted access
now we're going to do is we're going to
add
cancelled out read 9 so that our program
will close at one word
now say was your username
if I type in so this in carriages on so
as to say one two three four five
6789 10 every prayer
press enter into say you have been
granted access now fleet I
anything else that's not equal to 10
so it's just easier the more than 10
it's not going to say anything
such as go back in here and at a simple
else know you do
is when a new console dot right line
your username
is not the right Lee
so now we run this you know say what is
your username
so we type something that's not 10
catches on it was a
your username is not the right lead now
we can also do it said abusing
if username dot link equals Ted we use
go ahead
in do if he is not username startling
dot equals inside the arguments for
equals
you know ask us for and object as
integer
so we'll go ahead and do 10 right there
this is just another way that you could
test the leaked value
views in a and I equals can be used for
a lot of others
other things in Visual Basic so if you
read this it should work so
1,2,3,4,5,6,7 a 9
10 you know say you have been great
granted access
now this is a really simple to simple
tutorial
annisten after practice it and go ahead
and stay tuned for the next tutorial and
exhorted