hello youtube Sam hear from you to dot
com slash on live gamer for the New
Boston
editorial we're gonna be taking a look
at substrings
basically we're substring is is
extracting
part of a string a certain amount of
characters from a string
so let's go and you started and make a
little demo for this
so here's our main cell or gonna go
ahead and do is create a variable
so we'll just make this use a string as
string
and we'll see nothing an hour gonna do
is we're going to prompt the user to
into industry so console
die right line enter a
strain now or going to lose weight and
get their string
you should be very familiar with this
okay so now we're going to do is win a
print out the link that string
so for Southwest just at some space here
so that will create an empty line and
they will see
what the program pappas anne Taintor
line just so easy to read inside a
barred console window
now or gonna do israeli consul to
right line use a string
dot link image go ahead and convert that
to a string
so basically what we've done is we've
printed out
you for sharing that link was gets a
link to the string which went ahead and
compare that to a string
and left empty parameters right here so
now
we're going to you get some substrings a
use a string
so which is going to you cancelled
outright line
ever gonna do
use a string dots substring
inside of our parameters
we're going to have to arguments you
know have the start index
we're going to have the wing so we're
just gonna start
at zero and will print out the first 3
characters
this string so whenever you working with
the substring
strings always start at zero so let's
say you have
a use a string and you get the link to
that whenever you're counting to that
link is gonna start as you're so the
latest 12
is gonna go from 0 to 11 because as
twelve and values
but they always start 0 so they will
just go ahead
and do this a couple more times the dot
substring and will start at three
and we'll go ahead three characters and
then we're gonna do
is we're going to do this one more time
you but we're going to do a little bit
differently
be so instead abusing
to arguments for the prime matters at
the substring which can go ahead
and you use a string dot substring
so what this is gonna do
is gonna print out the first 3
characters at use a string
this gonna print out the third 26
characters abuse a string
Indian is gonna print out the remaining
characters abusers doing
so if we go ahead and run this is going
to say
interesting so we'll just type
on life came in and they were the same
so and once again we get that
air that I always run into ok it's such
a nice again
soldiers type on life
gamer same and you can see that
it tells us that the link that on that
MSM is 14
and its gonna tell us that the first 3
characters
at this string I here's is onal the next
the characters
is I V E and in the remaining characters
is gamer Sam so go ahead
and you can pat is a little bit with
substrings and then once you get that
now down
go ahead and move on to the next
tutorial