hello youtube same here from YouTube dot
com slash
on live gamer for the New Boston
editorial we're gonna be looking at a
couple of ways to format strings
so let's go and get started here is our
program
we have our main sad every gonna go
ahead and type in
so we're creative a book on my string
now or gonna do
is we're gonna prompt the user to
injury in a string so
console dot right line
please
enter a string now it's can get whatever
they entered in store as my string
now or going to do is we're going to ask
him for
a double value so cancelled outright lie
please
enter a decimal value now it's can get
whatever they typed in store it as a
double
so diem my double
as double is going to be equal to you
whatever they type in a case now or
gonna do
is reformatted strings so we're just
gonna
go ahead and U console dot right line to
give us some space
and now we're gonna format are stirring
incited arguments cancelled outright
line
so cancelled I right line we're gonna
start by typing the string key word
they were going to use a dot separator
to see what kinda methods there are
okay subs are available for us to use
for string so here's the format one that
we were using this as replaces one or
more
for madams is specified string with a
string representation a specified object
maybe we're using to %um you really have
to pay attention to that description
right now
let's go ahead and type format ever
gonna have to ask arguments for this
and first argument is going to be
enclosed in quotes
and this is where we're going to use to
tell Visual Basic how to format a string
so to start with a0 Colin in
to go enclose your braces there
and they're going to have a common and
after the comment will especially
specify which train to format it and
we're going to use my double so
basically what this does is it takes my
double formatting converted to a string
and you may be wondering what this means
well this means take any
take all at the numbers on the left side
the
the period and show them but only show
two spaces to the left side the period
so that had a really long a decimal
number
in only show the first two decimal
places now or gonna do
israeli I'm a show you a couple ways to
format a string so
was to console die right by and was
gonna take their strain which is my
string
ever gonna do dot to after
it's going to take their string thank
you for everything to uppercase
then we can also do cancelled outright
lied
my string dot to
lower and now if we chat con sadat
redline
to pass the program let's go ahead and
run this and see what happens
so its good assets for string
so the side on live gamer and what hath
assets for a decimal value soldiers type
really long decimal value
you can see that
it formats the decimal value to forty
3.23
it takes our string and covers all up to
uppercase and it takes a converted to
lowercase
are in the summer time to show you what
happens when we can personally to a
lower case
so enter in all caps chain
and winter a decimal value
and you can see that it formats our
decimal value in Atacama right here
just to make it look better so 2,342
that 23 and you can see here
that it took our string in Cumbria are
to uppercase
S's artie was a ver que si in you don't
see a change here
you can see that it takes it and covers
all to lower case
noses say few simple ways to format
strings and decimal numbers
and I have want you got that now down go
ahead and move on to the next door in
and thanks for watching