hello youtube same here from YouTube dot
com slash
on live gamer for the New Boston an
initiatory we'll be taking a look
at replacing parts a mystery so let's go
ahead and get started
we come over here to new project it was
opens our new project window for going
to select
a consul application am skinny carmine
replacing substrings
and the police appear a bit Athens go
ahead and click OK
initial our project
a case another project is loaded let me
go ahead and zoom in here bit
a case another project has voted
we're gonna go ahead and create a new
variable so was caught my string
ever going to create
a second able I wanna call it final
string
okay so now or gonna do
is we're going to prompt the user to
injury in any string
so which is going to tie
console die right by please
enter a strain now or gonna do is really
get what they typed in
so my string equals console dot
redline okay so after we get what they
typed in
we're gonna go ahead and remove part
that string
or replace that part gnashing with
another string so we're gonna type
final string equals
my stream if there were any news dot to
see what we can use for my string
they see it as a whole bunch stuff here
we're gonna type
replace now we're gonna do
is very go we're gonna go through here
and
we will just type in the first argument
a inside quotes
which is the all that I the value that
we want to replace
ever gonna replace a with the new value
so let's just do and and it finally
we will write that out on the console
and they were just Yukon sadat
read by so wat stressed input something
for it closes
and I are going to start running this
program its gonna say please enter
string
so I types and a.m. dog
cat Cal
astronomy
now for press enter
you can see that of the A's room were
replaced with an in
so here we have Sam and you can see down
here its
s im a cat was replaced with an N
and this is in shock to me it said
astronomy
so we can also do this with something
larger than just one character supply
type: hello in here
we can replace it with say goodbye
now if I type in something like
hello our live gamer
is to replace it with goodbye on that
game now
if you don't type hello in the first
rain it's not going to replace it at all
and I just so you know i right here
serve I just typed the New Boston here
it is going to give me the New Boston
back because didn't find
hello anyways I that's tree so this is a
pretty
a simple tutorial thanks for watching
what you guys have this
and nail down you know how to do it go
ahead and move on to the next tutorial