hello youtube same here from YouTube dot
com slash on live gamer for the New
Boston
and this tutorial we'll be taking a look
at comparing strings
says go and get started we're gonna come
down here
under our main cell and we're going to
create a couple variables
we'll start off by creating a string
so we'll just call it users stream
as string elsa equal to nothing
and they will declare another string
computer string
as string they will set that one equal
to
on live gamer now or gonna do
is we're going to prompt the user to
enter in a string so
console dot right line please
enter a stream so there was shelling get
what they type in
said that we have with it acted we're
going to use the string doc compare
function
so we're gonna console dot right wine
and which can it typed
string dot compare every reply going to
compare
user string to
computer string so that is our two
arguments for our string to compare the
first one
is the showing that where going to ca
that we're going to compare to the first
ring
so here if you understand what that
means
a good show you so they will do console
to reason I'd
now we run this you can see that I type
on live gamer
it had s is going to give me the value
of one
because it is comparing destroying to
the second-string now if we replace
these
input it backwards
we're going to get a value have -1
you can see out there that gives us -1
because instead of comparing the string
that they gave us
to the first ring were comparing the
first string to string that they gave us
there might be a little confusing but
I'm you can mess around
if you want and now we can also make
this
case insensitive so even if they make
the whole thing in capital letters
comparing it to this right here is going
to give us
a value of $0 so all she had to do this
which can type use a string and we're
going to compare that to computer string
in for a third argument it's got ignore
case
as boolean right here which can attack
true
so that I can type it anywhere they want
they can type it
all caps all lower case they can switch
off between cap similar case
whatever they want to do and I it %uh
still
give us a correct value so
if I type quite a bit like this
is going to give us a value of $0
because it compares a case-insensitive
and it just checked to see if these are
the same
as on live gamer so
that was a pretty simple tutorial you
can use this
for a bunch of different things in your
programs
and go ahead clear out the I get used to
it and what you don't that
go ahead and move on to the next
tutorial