hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash on live gamer for the New
Boston
in this tutorial we'll be taking a look
at the
Select Case statement now this like a
safe statement is very similar to the
if statement but sometimes you need to
use a slight case instead
if because it's a lot more efficient and
arts wat
this to you as we start programming so
it's going to get started
we're gonna create a variable and we'll
call it my int
and we're just going to make any integer
it's now Roy
what we're gonna do is work going to you
get the integer from the user
such as ask them for an integer
please
inter integer nodes can get with the
typing
and now we're going to do is we're going
to create Arcelik
Select Case statement so you start off
by typing select it says
runs one of several groups statements
depending on the value of an expression
so actor select where type
case there says the same thing
in our unity is we're going to type in
our variable that we can use for the
Select Case
statement so in our case we can use my
int
any Zune Press inter iMac the ads
and select for you so what it's like a
statement does
is that it starts off by checking the
first case
so let's just do case 0 console dot
right line
hello
in with you case
wide agency there that whenever you
create a case
you go into start by using the keyword
case
you can add whichever whatever you want
it to be so
in our case raising it suggests over the
integers equal to 0 thing I do this
and you can do this industry surveys
showing
is equal to this story here go ahead and
do whatever's in here
now as I saying I can in a row to myself
there
by with us like a statement the reason
it's more efficient than an if statement
is that ill go through and the start
it's like a statement in a case 0 is
true
in its gonna go ahead and in this led
k-state for you
diving it take a look at any other cases
you have see could have hundreds and
hundreds of cases
but as soon as it reaches the the one
case is looking for
you know exit your select k-state me now
if you use
if and else here then is going to
even though or excuse because it's going
to look at all the ALCS
and that's a reason you do when you
select case
over if Chelsea so
with us to case one will add a couple
more cases here
okay so now that we have three cases
we're gonna go ahead and run our program
yeah let's not forget to do cancelled
out remind so it's Rustin put something
for the program closes
and if we run this
it'll say please enter an integer
sofa type: 0 is gonna say hello
and will run this a couple more times
and go through each case
if we type 1 you know say bye and then
if we typed to you ill say good morning
so a site case statement
is fairly simple its quite similar to
the
else here and what you know that down
go ahead and move on to the next 20 and
we're gonna be learning more about us
like case and thanks for watching