hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash on live gamer for the New
Boston
and this tutorial we can be taking
another look at the Select Case
statement so
this time instead of using integer we're
going to use
a string so we're gonna start off by
creating a string
sodium my string as string
said that you were nothing now we're
going to do is we're going to
get my stream from the user so is gonna
ask them
two interesting in my string
it's going to be equal to console die
read line and now we're going to do is
restart
are select case statement so select
case my string gonna do it case
hello and wish to console died
right line could buy
and will do two more cases for the case
could buy then cancelled outright line
hello
now in a new case I'm
message to you fishing
and the Yukon so died right line
boat okay so now if we run this
it going to close out right before
it's done so you had cancelled out
redline
now in summer I very first tutorials I
said that
this will let you read the line or the
the program before it closes out
and that is true but what he actually
really does
is that it waits for you to press enter
so whatever's you type in there in the
line that it's reading
it's going to you I'm move on to the
next eight min 20 press ENTER so
depressed nothing press Enter
then to go ahead and in our case exit
the program because there's nothing
after this
let's go and run this and if we type
fishing is gonna say boat we have one
problem
problem with this if we typed fishing
with a capital have it's not going to
give us anything
so what we need to do is make this
case-insensitive
so to do this which can type
my string died to
lower and
we need to make sure that all OVR
strings in terror cases are lower case
and you can see they are we at hello
goodbye and fishing and they're all
lower case
now we run this we can type
fishing in
anyway we want is going to give us both
back now what other thing we need to
cover
is what happened to the type in
something that's not a nice like a
statement such as
dark it's not to return anything so
to deal with this we're going to use
what's called
case Ellis and this is very similar to
the
else in the Italian statement is going
to cover anything that you don't have in
your cases
so if my sing that to lower is equal to
anything
other than hello goodbye or fishing
it's going go ahead and we'll have it
right
consul dot right line I don't know what
you're talking about
so now we run this we can type in
anything in here
an assay I don't know what you're
talking about so this is a very
fairly simple tutorial but the stuff
attaching this is very usefull
and I'm going back to some so I K
statements when you have that now down
to have it
go ahead and move on to the next
tutorial and thanks for watching