hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash
on live gamer for the New Boston and its
adjoining
when we take a look at a for loop
now loops are a very important part of
programming
basically when loops do is it will
repeat
a syriza code or a block of code
for you a certain amount of times now
with the for loop
it does that Baku code however many
times you want it to you
in there are going to be using loops
that will do it based on
other things so let's go and get started
we're gonna go ahead and create a very
able
and we'll just call it in one
as integer now we're going to do
is we're going to create are for loop so
in sarra
plays in key word for ever going to
specify
int1 every insect in one equal or
something because is it
it with anything yet so now you can
start
41 and they were going to use the
keyword to
she's 220 and then you can see that
it adds and next for us so basically
what this does
is it takes it starts out with for which
tells it that we're going to be making a
loop
it takes int1 and says equal to 1
and it's going to do it from one to 20
so
the first time around for the it once
you meet your One
it when it comes back up to the top in
one is going to be equal to 2
and in three and then poor and so on and
so forth
so in one is gonna go all the way up to
and then once it hits 20 it'll run deep
the code the for loop on what time in
the most secret 21
it's not gonna do the for loop again so
to demonstrate this
hours type: consul da right wine
int1
is equal to and was gonna go ahead and
use our
inside and we're going to type int
1 so basically what this does is it says
in one is able to and it takes the
current value it wanted
because we don't know what were it one
is able to witness can
to but the variable name there now in a
new console
died redline and if we run this
you can see that it says
in was equal to 1 in one single to
it one is equal to 3 and it'll go all
the way down
until it one is equal to 20 now
you can change this number appeared to
do the
for loop as many times as you want so we
can even do it a hundred times
you can see that has
100 by Jay here it starts off with one
it goes all the way up to 100 but here
here's one thing
that will invalidate are for you and
keep you from running
so if we start out for it in one Eagles
won
in there we go to -1 you can see that
it won't print out anything because
default
for loops workout up one value so since
in one starts at one
whenever cuz whenever hits the next
keyword right here
gonna send it back up to this poor is
going to add 1281
it says it at one ads want it one in one
is now equal to 2
in our through for that goes to -1
so stuck in a rut all said I'll you've
learned a little bit about four lives
you can go ahead and make your own for
the and they're very useful
and we're gonna be using them a lot
later on in programming there's a lot of
other lives here milling about you gonna
be learning about
on so far within for each
they were going to learn do until do
while there's year while loops
and and there's a lot of other loops
that a very useful in programming
so thanks for watching and stay tuned to
the next tutorial