hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash on live gamer
for the New Boston and in this tutorial
we'll be taking a look at
step operators now the last tutorial we
did a simple for loop
and in that for the loop it
automatically
stepped it up by one each time the for
loop ran now
sometimes you won't want to do that
maybe you want to step it by
by or step by even 100
there's an easy way to do this by using
what's called the step operator
and you can also step negative numbers
to says go ahead and create a little
demo application for this
going up to new project
were consul application and we will
discard
step operator and we'll just go ahead
and click
okay that's two men to be here
okay sources add console dot
redline so waits for us to press ENTER
or closer to the program
for it to em close the window before
I'm we're done reading so I'm let's go
ahead and create
a for the sewing 24 no more I'm
equals 1 to 20 and it was to console
doubt right line
no one now into making a for loop
you don't have to declare the variable
name one I know I did and my last
tutorial
but it isn't necessary you can if you
want to you
a case and I we got this
for the done as go ahead and you consul
dot right line appear
normal for you
and let's create
another for the so for now I'm one
Eagles won 220 and then let's just do
cancelled outright line
no
one now these are exactly the same
but we can do something very simple to
make and completely different so for no
more niggas 12 20
and we just call the step operator
incest specifies how much to implement
between each loop iteration
so that basically says whenever he gets
down to the next
you whatever is after stat is going to
be how much it adds to
now I'm one so it's go ahead and let's
step
5 in this for the so
less come up here intact cancelled I
right line
and then we'll do another one just saw
it at the space
in between are four leaves and what to
say step by
5 us create one more for them
to console dot right line don't do that
one more time
but in this on to say step
by negative 4
says create one more for the
so for now I'm one equals 20
to 1 and with this step that
by negative for so what this is gonna do
is gonna start for the past 20
and go down for each time into it gets
and wish to console dot right line
no one
says go and run a program
and see what happens okay so appear
we have are normal for loop which starts
at one
and goes all the way tony An cast by one
each time in Frisco down a bit
we have our step by by starts out at one
at five to which Q g6 then gives you 11
in is the 16 they can see it in pre
anything else after sixteen
and the reason it does is because if you
at 5:16 is gonna be 21
nashnamie out at the balance the loop
that we set and here's our step by -4
it starts out to any two tracks for from
it which is
which makes 16 niggers and 12 than a
then for and it doesn't go down easier
because once again
that would be at the balance that we
separate the loop now step
is a very simple thing to learn and it's
very useful though
and I find myself using a lot when I
make programs as so go ahead
and give it a try make some programs are
the and then once you get that down
go ahead and move on to the next
tutorial so thanks for watching