hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash
on live gamer for the New Boston in this
tutorial
we're going to be taking a look at
exiting a for loop
early now it's going to get started
will create a new project liked consul
application
and we'll just name it exit for Lou and
then click OK
now is wait for to our project and zoom
in a bit here
okay so now let's go ahead
and creator for versus type
cancelled outright lied immodest label
this one
as normal for loop now let's go ahead
and create
a simple for them so for no Moines
equals 1 to 30 let's go ahead
and printout num 1 so canceled our
right line no wine
so this is a very
fairly simple for the now she's at a
space here
so they're being empty line announced
tell them
that this is a for loop that is exited
went numb one is equal to a certain
value
so consul to right line for a loop
that exits before it's finished
so now it's great another for the so for
now I'm one
equals 1 230 let's go ahead and do
console dar
right line no
white okay so now we're gonna do
is we're going to test the value of Nome
wine
to see if it's equal or something and if
it is they were gonna go ahead and exit
before that so we gonna do this by using
a simple
a statement so if no Moines equals
23 then
what are we gonna do which can use the
keyword exit which is
exit procedure a block in chance for his
execution immediately to the statement
following the procedure call
or block definition so basically what
that means
is that if no more physical 23 is gonna
hit is
exit statement its gonna skip all the
way down to this I'm right here I'm
typing is coming
because that is
after the if statement and after the for
that so now if we go ahead and run this
see it closes their
go ahead and Yukon so I
redline
cases going to go to the top agencies as
normal for the
he says one two three four five and so
on
all the way down into it gets the value
30 announces
for the exits before it's finished it
started the value or in
he goes all the way down to the value 23
and
exits the former now we can also do this
if we step the value so for number one
Eagles 12 30 as we step by for
then you can see that
is this is Damon is never gonna rent so
if we run this
using its always 29 and it doesn't stop
at 24
so we can do is we can do if num 1
is a load here
okay so if num 1 is greater than 23
then exit the for loop see can see that
egos 159 1317
2125 and then exits for the
because now I'm one is greater than 23
so
go ahead and make a couple for loops
that exit
under certain condition in what you got
that down
in you remember it go ahead and move on
to the next tutorial so thanks for
watching