hello youtube same here from youtube.com
size on live gamer for the New Boston
and St George we're gonna be taking work
at the continue statement
now what this does is let's say you
making for the
and it's for GNOME one equals 1 230
now let's say if no more days ago 23
in you don't want it to run that
iteration of the for the
so it will print out assay would have
cancelled outright
I know one and you don't want 23 to
print out
you would use if number one equals 23
then continue for so basically what that
does is it
skips that iteration the for loop moves
on to the next one
so I let's go ahead and make some
examples of this so what type cancelled
outright lied
normal for the it will make up for the
Asus 215 you cancelled I
right line nom
1 so basically where this is going to do
is just gonna write out 13 15
on our consul now it's at a space here
and ice to you
continue statement a case and asked
maker for the
that has the continue statement it so to
start off by using the four key word
will create a random one variable and
we'll go to 15
that number one can only be accessed
inside this for the
and nowhere else because we didn't
actually declared says go ahead
and type a simple if statement so
if number one is
equal to 5 then what we want to do
was typed continue for
so this is going to do is is gonna skip
the iteration
no more if numb 105 its gonna skip
whatever code comes after this
now his here's a check that I wanna
teach you guys in the city were
if you haven't if statement with only
one might have
might occur in between in India you can
just go ahead and take out India
in do this instead so
if num 1 equals five dead continue
for by doing this you don't have to have
the in if statement and your code is a
lot and neater
and easier to read so
now that we have a if statement and with
just you console
da right line no
1 so if we go and run this
we're going to get
in our normal for the it says one
2345 6789 10
11 12 13 14 15 you can see that all the
numbers are there
benefit cannot hear the car continues
David
you can see it looks like other numbers
there but we're missing a five-minute in
between for
and six now
let's do this for a couple other values
so let's go ahead
and create a multiplied if statement so
if no money aside then continue 4 that's
just sad
and or operator so
if someone Eagles 5 or no more in is
equal to you
8 or numb one is
equal to you let's say 12 so
we can really have to make that will
delight will just go ahead and put this
right after that
okay said I was gonna do
is gonna skip to number five 8 in 12 so
if we run this
we're going to get 12 346
7 its gonna skip a is easy if I
any of the skipped 12 so go ahead
and practice some continue for statement
you can
come up with different ways to use it
within your program and I want you know
how to do that United forget it
the go ahead and move on to the next
tutorial