hello youtube same here from you to dot
com slash on that game it for the New
Boston
and this tutorial gonna be taking a look
at the do
until loop so now basically what to do
until it appears
is it similar to the for the in that it
will do a certain block of code
over and over again until a certain
value is reached
but the differences is that when you use
a for loop
the development knows exactly how many
times that for the is going to run
so let's say we did Fortnum one equals 1
to 20 we know that that's gonna go
twenty ties because we specified
that it needs to go that many times now
the do until loop
it will run and until
a certain value is reached and now
sometimes this around
unless it for example we make it due
into
I do until number one equals
10 is good run ten times or it could
write it thousand times
if no more in is equal to let's say
negative 990 there around a thousand
times
now let's go ahead and make a do until
example so go ahead and select a new
project
will do a console application and will
type
do until now it's humid here
okay that's go ahead and add console dot
redline so I won't forget that at the
end and now it's come up here
and will declare a variable sodium gnome
one
as integer and we'll set it equal to
negative well she said it was 0-2 start
with
a case in our what we're going to do
is we are are going to create are do
until
so tight do until numb one is equal to
let's do 10 and you can see here that
create this
loop word for us so basically what this
means is
is similar to the next in the for the 10
hits this day be right here
is good come back around to the top do
until then
and if num 1 is not equal to 10
that is gonna go ahead and keep looping
until them one is equal to 10
instead go down to the line after the
loop statement okay so what we want to
do and tell them what is it will attend
so decide consul to right line
no one now
if we run this the new we it will print
out
0 over and over and over again because
we have in committed
no more it's always going to be quite a
zero so it's just you
after concert outright line on one was
typed number one
place equals 1 so basically what this is
gonna do
is going to print out no boy this can
add one to it is your
is going to loop until number is
acquitted is gonna do counsel to
relied sega's if you read this
egos one 2345
6789 now you can see that it stops at
night
the reason it does is is because it does
it until then one Eagle said
so if num what is the quality and is not
going to do it now if we set the equal
to 11
that it would turn out all the way up to
10 now we can also a permit number one
in different values
so can you know my own place equals two
a conceive we run this week 02 4628
now can also set no mind to a different
value other than zero at the beginning
so be set equal to -20 if we go ahead
and do until numb one equals 10 is going
to do it
a different Amanda times says gonna
start native 20 -18 as
it committed by two all the way until he
gets to 8 so
go ahead and practice im a couple do 12
lives
I want you got those down you know
you're not gonna forget him go ahead and
move on to the next tutorial
and thanks for watching guys