hello youtube same here from YouTube dot
com slash
on life gamer for the New Boston
anticipatory ok we're going to be taking
a look
at the do while loop so basically what
to do while loop is
is its sounds very similar to do until
loop
but the concept of the is completely
opposite
now I mean by this is that the do until
you
will perform ace said code
until a value or until something is true
now the do while loop is completely
opposite
it will perform a block of code
while a value is true and that was that
value is false its gonna stop
so this go ahead and make a couple
demoss this
so go ahead and make a new project we
will call it
do while loop make sure you've selected
consul application
and go ahead and click okay
so does give their second to load here
assume in a bit
does go ahead and add
console dot redline so I don't forget to
retire on our program
announced come up right about that we're
going to create a variable
so we use the dim keyword was caught
number one
as integer and we'll set it equal to 0
us go ahead and make our do while loop
so we're Sarah by using the do keyword
which
the description says a pizza box
statement into a balloon
billion condition is true so now we're
going to add
while so repeats a blog statements while
able
boo the condition is true so do while
downwind is less than or equal to
15 now you can see that as the loop for
us so they're a loop back up to do while
statement
and after every iteration of the loop
you can see we did less than or equal to
15% in this
now if we just did lesson 15 did it
would trade out until I got to 14
and it would stop so we did at the equal
so
corporate all the way to fifteen so wish
to cancel
to right line no
1 okay so now we're going to take a
minute numb one
because we don't is just gonna run
forever so
will go ahead and you know I'm one plus
equals 1
now you can see that if we run this we
get
0 215 sweetness love you
I don't know why it's been doing this to
me lately but on this go ahead
and we'll take this table right here
number one place equals 1
well cut that out and they were at it
before our print statement or outright
lied statement so basically what it's
going to do is connect
at 12 noon first to name one first and
that is going to bring it out
so we're gonna start at the value wind
into all the way to
sixty now you may be wondering why is a
go to 16
well because in the last one we had no
one possible swine
after our costs a lot right line so it
was equal to 16
actually pointed out 15 ended up back to
top it said ok no its not less than
equal to 15 so it's going quite out of
this
okay
so if we do no more impossible's on
before
it will go to 16 and then it'll come
back up and say oh it's a lot less
illegal
15 let's go ahead and exit out here so
I'm
that was a quick tutorial on how to do
do while lives go ahead practice and do
I live some doing to loosen the tutorial
before this too what you got us down go
ahead and devices next tutorial
and thanks for watching