hello youtube same here from you dot com
slash
OnLive game it for the New Boston in
this tutorial we'll be taking a look
at quitting your do loops early dinosaur
for do while loops or do want to lose
now if you remember back we learned how
to quit
for loops early now the same concept can
be applied to you
do until I do while loops that's right
get started
and make a little devil application so
go ahead and slight console application
and will type this quitting
do loops
go ahead and click okay so it's humid
zone here
and ass go ahead and add
consul dot read line okay so now let's
create
our do and to so this to do
until Nam 1 equals
10 the go ahead and loop
those to appear and create now
one so
declared a blind as integer and we will
set it equal to see
so
I see well as you we're going to do
until one accosted
and wheel console dot right line no
1 now we're going to do
is we're going to in commit them one so
if you run this
it's going to give us your own two three
four five six seven eight nine
not sad a simple its statement so
if numb
wind equals 5
did exit
do so well is gonna do is
whenever it comes down actually are due
until statement each time it loops its
gonna hit this
if statement right here and then if
number one is equal to five then
exit do so system one such as you
is gonna run through this is can be fine
is can equal to 1
in Syria down and the one single spine
is an exit do
so our programs gonna put out 01 234
because is gonna exit was equal spy
let's go and read this
you can see here that we have zero one
two three four
now we can also do this
with a do while so do while
numb one is less than
or equal to 10 so
if number one is equal to 5% did exit
the do it's going to change it will be
here with you is number one is equal to
7%
so you can see here that we get zero
one 23 456 and then it exits
now we can also do
is let's say our do while loop is
not incrementing by one so what if it
skips the number five well what we can
do it said Oh
is number one equals five we can do if
someone
is greater than by so season commit this
by
to you can see here that we're gonna get
0 to for and now
you can see that stopped before it got
to fight because number one was verified
now if we do it like this then it's
gonna free now all the way
in this if statement is never gonna run
so go ahead
and make a couple doing two loops that
exit based on certain conditions you can
do it differently than I did
I encourage you to do that so you can
learn more about the programming
and then once you've got that down go
ahead and move on to the next tutorial
and thanks for watching